# Noe Nieto - Software Engineering

Noe Nieto is an Electronics Engineer with 5 years of experience in software development with Python, PHP, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Linux, MySQL and PostgreSQL. He is helping companies in Mexico and Argentina to develop beautiful and functional web applications.

# Personal information

Full name:

Noe Misael Nieto Arroyo

Age:

31

Phone (mobile):

+52 (686) 5477677

E-mail:

nnieto@noenieto.com

#### **Nationality:**

- Mexican (Detailed information is available upon request)
- Can travel to the United States with Visa B1/B2

#### Find out more about me in the following web sites

- My personal blog http://blog.noenieto.com
- LinkedIn Profile http://www.linkedin.com/profile/view?id=84300665
- MasterBranch https://masterbranch.com/tzicatl
- GitHub https://github.com/tzicatl
- BitBucket http://dev.noenieto.com/
- Twitter https://twitter.com/tzicatl

## **Skills**

#### · Software libraries and frameworks

- For web development Plone, Zope and Grok Pyramid Django CakePHP JQuery, jQueryTools, jQueryUI, AngularJS CoffeeScript
- For databases SQL, MySQL and PostgreSQL. SQLAlchemy, ZODB
- For linux applications Gstreamer Gtk+ / PyGtk

#### · Testing and automated testing

• For python applications - I've used the following frameworks for testing my applications: Unittest, zope.testing, zope.app.testing, plone.app.testing and Selenium

#### · Programming, scripting and markup Languajes

- High proficiency Python, C, JavaScript, HTML, XML, CSS, Bash, JSON, XSLT, ZCML, PHP
- Medium proficiency C++, Java, Matlab, Assembler (Mainly for PICs and 8051).
- Low proficiency C#, Perl, .NET, Ruby.

#### • Development Tools

- · Compilers and build systems zc.buildout, Python setuptools, GNU Makefile and autotools.
- Automated testing Python unittest, plone.app.testing, zope.testing, PhantomJS and JasmineJS.
- Source Code Management tools Git, Mercurial, Bazaar and Subversion.

#### · Linux server administration

- More than 10 years as daily desktop machine, and 6+ years as linux sysadmin for web servers.
- Proficient with Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora, CentOS, RHEL and Amazon's AMI.
- Confiuration and management of different opensource RDBMS like MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, and ZODB. Sizes range from 1mb to 150 GB.
- DevOps: Amazon Web Services, Fabric (python).

#### • Electronics Engineering

- Data acquisition systems (Voltage, Current, Pressure, Fuel flow, and Vibration).
- Experience with the following systems/brands: Dewetron/Dewesoft, Scanivalve, LEM, B&K, Ectron and Ametek.
- Hardware platforms: NI PXI, Dewetron, Scanivalve, LDS Genesis.

## **Education**

Proof of achievements can be requested personally.

- Instituto Tecnológico de Mexicali Master's degree in Electronics Engineering
  - Only first two semesters.
  - Time span: Between August 2007 and June 2008.
- Arizona State University. Data Acquisition training seminar by JACMET group
  - This course is part of a series that leads to a JACMET Engineering Instrumentation Certificate. This course takes a practical viewpoint and covers the specification, application and extendibility of data acquisition systems.
  - Time span: Three weeks on September 2006.
- Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla Electronics Engineering
  - Instrumentation and control specialization.
  - Kalman filter simulator as internship project on "Centro de Ingenieria" INAOE.
  - Installation of a 8-node cluster in the parallel computing research laboratory of the Instituto Tecnologico de Puebla as social service.
  - My Thesis "Sistema de Vigilancia con video sobre TCP/IP" demostrates the possibility to build surveillance systems by using only Free Software and Open Source tools like Linux and Gstreamer.
  - Time span: Between August 2000 and December 2006. Thesis defense on September 2012.
- Universidad Popular Autónoma del Estado de Puebla Computer programmer technician (diploma)
  - Proficient in C, Basic and Pascal.
  - Time span: 1997 to 2000

# **Professional Experience**

Proof of employment and references can be requested personally.

- NNieto Consulting Services Freelancer
  - This is my own company, I provide software development services and training. On this project I've worked with different companies and intitutions across the country and abroad.
    - WAM Ready2Fill (http://Ready2Fill.com/). Python training course for web development.
    - Editorial AlfaOmega (http://libroweb.alfaomega.com.mx/). Systems engineering and development.
    - Centro de Psiquiatría y Psicología Holokinética (http://www.holokinesislibros.com/). Research, design, development and comissioning of e-commerce site for books, audios and DVD's.

- Universidad Pedagógica Nacional (http://www.upn.mx/). Systems administration and consulting.
- HomeViva, an Argentinian startup (http://www.homeviva.com). Systems engineering, research, development and operation.
- Time span: From April 2011 up to now.
- Locations: Puebla, Mexico City, Mexicali, Guadalajara and Saltillo.

#### • iServices de México - Web/Python developer

- In charge of integration/development and maintenance of their in-house LCMS systems. My activities involved Linux System administration, project management, Web Software development, Software engineering and maintenance with the Plone CMS and emergency assistance in case of software failure.
- Time span: January 2009 until April 2011.
- · Location: Puebla and Mexico City.

### • Honeywell Aerospace de Mexico - Data Acquisition Engineer

- As a Data Acquisition Engineer I was in charge of the commissioning and operation of hardware and software. I also played a developer role for in-house software tools. Also, I was specialist in pressure, temperature, voltage, current and vibration measurements as well as video over IP and networking. Our team was also in charge of assuring that our instruments were always calibrated with traceability to the NIST and always ready for use, that included dealing with purchasing and supply chain departments.
- Wide experience in Video Over IP and Networking as a result of intern projects.
- Time span: From May 2006 until December 2008
- · Location: Mexicali, Phoenix.

#### • Gameloft S de RL - Multiplayer programmer

- Implement test and deploy modifications of the multiplayer server (written in C++) and multiplayer API used in networked games for mobile phones.
- Implement, test and deploy modifications needed to support specific models of cellphones by the different game titles published by Gameloft.
- Time span: February to May, 2006.
- · Location: Mexicali.
- Centro de ingenieria Instituto Nacional de Astrofísica Óptica y Electrónica Internship. Embedded systems laboratory assistant
  - Work related to data acquisition, real time, tracking and control systems.
  - Time span: 2006.
  - Location: Tonanzintla (Puebla).

#### • FreeLance IT Consultant

• Basic computer training and computer technician. Installation of voice and data networks, independent software developer.

• Time span: 2000 - 2005

· Location: Puebla.

# Training and conventions

- Seminario de Aplicaciones de las Tecnologías de la Información y Comunicaciones Sept. 3rd-7th, Instituto Tecnológico de Puebla, Mexico
  - Speaker. One 45 minute talk about basic multimedia applications with GStreamer.
  - Trainer. Five-hour Python course for newcomers. Attendants included students and teachers of the IT Academia of the ITP.
- PyCON US 2012 March 7th-15th, Santa Clara, CA.
  - · Conference attendant and sprinter.
  - Attended to the tutorial DevOps for Python: Doing More With Less https://us.pycon.org/2012/schedule/presentation/286/
- FLISOL 2011 April 9th, Puebla, Puebla
  - Speaker. I talked a bit about the GStreamer Framework.
- PyCON US 2011 March 9th-17th, Atlanta, GA.
  - Conference attendant and sprinter.
- PyCON US 2010 March, Atlanta, GA.
  - · Conference attendant and sprinter.
- PyCON US 2009 March, Chicago, IL.
  - Conference attendant and sprinter.